<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>docker on Q</title>
    <link>https://19xx.dev/tags/docker/</link>
    <description>Recent content in docker on Q</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 02 Apr 2014 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://19xx.dev/tags/docker/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Building Docker images on Travis.ci</title>
      <link>https://19xx.dev/posts/0000-Building-Docker-images-on-Travis.ci/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Apr 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://19xx.dev/posts/0000-Building-Docker-images-on-Travis.ci/</guid>
      <description>Olá!
Inspired by the posts from Viktor Adam&amp;rsquo;s blog, when I have some spare time I have been playing with Docker and some open source tools to build this blog.
So far I have my two little devices a Raspberry Pi and a Rock64 hosting this blog, yes, that&amp;rsquo;s right, you&amp;rsquo;re reading this straight from a Ghost blog behind an NGinx hosted at my home, be nice and say hi!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Home made Kubernetes cluster</title>
      <link>https://19xx.dev/posts/0006-Home-made-Kubernetes-cluster/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Apr 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://19xx.dev/posts/0006-Home-made-Kubernetes-cluster/</guid>
      <description>Homemade Kubernetes Cluster #  In my previous post, I wrote about how to set up a scalable Jenkins using Kubernetes at home on top of home devices, in my case, 3 Raspberries, 2 Rock64 and a NUC. Since it wasn&amp;rsquo;t a 5 minutes task I&amp;rsquo;ll describe here the steps I went through to get it working.
Pre-checks #  Before installing Kubernetes you better check which Docker version is supported by the Kubernetes version you intend to install, a few days ago I upgraded my Kubernetes cluster from version 12 to 15 so, version 15 is what I&amp;rsquo;ll be used as a reference here.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Jenkins&#43;Kubernetes</title>
      <link>https://19xx.dev/posts/0007-Jenkins&#43;Kubernetes/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Apr 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://19xx.dev/posts/0007-Jenkins&#43;Kubernetes/</guid>
      <description>How to Setup Scalable Jenkins on Top of a Kubernetes Cluster (At Home). #   Before we start, I&amp;rsquo;ll make some intro about the scenario and reasons for my choices, if you prefer, skip this part, the meat of the article starts at the Docker section.
 A few days ago I decided to start a new side project, a tool that will take care of a bunch of things I need; I pay for different ones, and yet they don&amp;rsquo;t cover everything I need.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Terraform</title>
      <link>https://19xx.dev/posts/0005-Terraform/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Apr 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://19xx.dev/posts/0005-Terraform/</guid>
      <description>TLDR; A walk through an EC2 instance setup, dynamically attaching volumes snapshots and configuring Cloudflare DNS entries pointing to the new instance using Terraform and Docker (Ghost, Traefik).
Source code: https://github.com/allandequeiroz/blog/tree/extract_variables
Basic infrastructure configuration using Terraform, Docker (Ghost, Traefik) and Cloudflare. #  For a while, I&amp;rsquo;ve hosted this blog, at home, using Docker and Kubernetes across a few Raspberries (I use it as an excuse to do play around). It turns out that I&amp;rsquo;m moving to a new place, so I have a new excuse to play with something else.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
